我们昨天得知了一个坏消息
We got some bad news yesterday.
菲尔的妈妈去世了
Phil's mom died.
倒也不是意料之外
It wasn't unexpected.
菲尔陪在她身边
He was with her.
她在睡梦中平静地走了
And she went very peacefully and asleep.
我跟她有种特殊的感情
She and I had a special connection.
我们都有
We all did.
但主要是我
But mostly me.
她说我和她很像
She said I was just like her.
怎么 她也争强好胜到古怪的地步吗
What? Is she weirdly competitive too?
明天全家人都要去佛罗里达
The whole family is going down to Florida tomorrow
陪菲尔参加葬礼
to be with Phil for the service.
真是莫大的安慰
Such a relieve.
我能感觉到他现在是多么需要我
I can feel how much he needs me right now.
终于来了
There they are.
小家伙们好啊
Hey, guys.
你把我的护颈枕都带来了
Oh, you brought my nap pillow.
我好想你啊
I missed you so much.
菲尔 我真遗憾
Phil, I'm so sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
格蕾丝是个善良又古怪的女人
Grace was such a kind and whimsical soul.
她给动物戴鹿角拍照片做成的圣诞贺卡
The different animals she put antlers on for christmas cards--
太有创见了
Inspired.
每张都是实拍 绝无PS伪造
Not a single one was photoshopped.
鳄鱼的也是吗
Not even the alligator?
害她被咬掉了小拇指尖
Cost her the tip of her pinkie,
但她无怨无悔
but she had no regrets.
你们能来我真的很高兴
I'm so glad you guys are here.
希望请假没有让你为难
I hope it wasn't too hard to get away from work.
不会 拜托 为家人做任何事都可以
No. Please, anything for family.
能离开办公室 让我做任何事都可以
Anything to get me out of that office.
无聊的文件 开不完的会
It's all boring paperwork and endless meetings.
说真的 这场葬礼来得太是时候了
Honestly, this funeral could not have come at a better time.
真会说话 你该把这句话写在花签上
Aw, that's sweet. You should put that on the flowers.
歌洛莉亚 穿成这样一定很热吧
Gloria, you must be so hot in that.
我这是服丧
I am in mourning.
在哥伦比亚 丧礼是很严肃的事情
In Columbia, we take death very seriously.
在哪儿不是呢
Where don't they?
能把面纱摘了吗
Can we lose the veil?
没有人要抓你 歌洛莉亚
Nobody's looking for you, Gloria.
谁是歌洛莉亚
Who is Gloria?
我在佛罗里达被通缉
I am a wanted woman in Florida.
我曾在那里居住过 我离开时
I used to live there, and when I left,
我的室友把我们的公寓改造成了妓院
my roommate made our apartment into a house of prostitution,
而那时租约上留的还是我的名字
and my name was still on the lease.
其实就跟个交通罚单差不多
It's like a traffic ticket.
去趟法院 交个罚款 就完事儿了
You walk into court, pay a fine, it's done.
"快速"又"简单"
Quick and easy.
是啊 那家妓院就叫这名字
Yes, that was the name of the whorehouse.
米奇尔 你能陪她上法院吗
Mitchell, can you go with her to court?
她需要个像样点的律师
She's gonna need some sort of lawyer.
杰 米奇尔现在真是疲惫不堪
Uh, you know, Jay, Mitchell is so burnt out right now.
他十分需要休息
He is in desperate need of a break.
法院传票不用脑子也能应付 拜托
Bench warrants are a no-brainer. And, I mean, come on.
歌洛莉亚看起来像那种
Does Gloria really look like the kind of woman
开妓院的女人吗
who would run a brothel?
-我还是陪她去吧 -你还是去吧
- Yeah, I better go with her. - You should go.
是啊
Yeah.
你们来了
There they are!
你真美 你好 克莱尔
Oh, you look beautiful. Hi, claire.
你还好吗
How are you holding on, hmm?
还好吧
Oh, well, you know...
我们会挺过去的 对吧 老爸
We're getting through it. Huh, dad?
我现在还好 就是有点失眠
Ah. I'm doing okay. A little trouble sleeping.
我习惯她的鼾声了
I'm so used to her snoring,
我可能得借一下邻居的牛头犬了
I may have to borrow the neighbor's bulldog.
早上好 夏洛特
Morning, Charlotte!
这是我从加州来的亲戚们
This is my family from California!
看得出来 看起来都跟电影明星似的
I can tell. They all look like movie stars.
谢谢
Ah. Oh, thank you.
真奇怪 我认识那女人
That's nuts. I know that woman,
但忘了在哪儿认识的
but I have no idea from where.
是啊 这地方充满了这样的故事
Yeah. This place is full of stories like that.
早上好 邓菲先生 客人们
Good morning, Mr. Dunphy, visitors.
拜托 雪莉 叫我弗兰克就好了
Please, Shelley, call me Frank.
不 先生
No, sir.
可能"呼啸松"那边会这么称呼业主
That might be the way they do things at Whistling Pines,
但我们"休闲园"的管理很规范严谨
But we run a tight ship here at Leisure Park.
根据你的要求 我预订了
As per your request, I have reserved
今晚的湖滨广场 时间为一小时
the lakeside promenade this evening for one hour,
从下午5点开始 供您开追悼会
Beginning at 5:00 p.m., for your memorial service.
顺便提醒您 广场上不能吸烟
May I remind you that there's no smoking on the grounds,
湖边不能带玻璃制品 不能喂鸭子
no glass near the lake, no feeding the ducks?
请您节哀顺变
And I'm sorry for your loss.
-谢谢 -不能喂鸭子
- Thank you. - No feeding the ducks.
你盯着我干什么
What are you looking at me for?
我真喜欢这里
I love it here--
修剪平整的草坪
manicured lawns,
活动计划周详 晚餐及时
planned activities, early dinners.
一个孩子还能要求什么呢
What more does a kid need?
是啊 每个人都这么有礼貌又体贴
Oh, yeah. And everyone's so polite and considerate--
不像基圈里那些无休止的明争暗斗
Nothing like the constant catfights in my circle,
每一周
where every week,
都有人会莫名其妙地生另一个人的气
somebody's mad at somebody for god knows who what,
而我总是被卷入其中
and I'm always thrown into the middle.
你好像很焦躁 他们这里有蒸汽房
You seem tense. You know, they have a steam room.
要跟我一起出出汗吗
Wanna join me for a schvitz?
拜托 这里可是佛罗里达
Please, it's Florida.
我想流汗的话 只要动动胳膊就行了
If I wanna sweat more, I'll just move my arms.
你去享受吧
You go have fun.
嘿 你
Hey, you.
你喜欢那本书吗
Are you liking that book?
虽然这不是我在机场买过的最差劲的东西
Well, it's not the worst thing I've picked up at an airport,
但也差不多了
but close.
这是什么情况
What is this,
是读书会还是选美大会啊
a book club or a Miss America Pageant?
我们在找下一本要读的书
We're looking for our next book.
你们现在读的是什么书
Oh, what are you reading now?
《无辜香吻之诱惑》
"Tempted by her innocent kiss."
你一定没听说过
I-I'm sure you don't know it.
拜托 达文·卡特是艾希莉的第一个男人
Oh, please. Devon Carter was Ashley's first,
她希望他们能激情永驻
she wants their passion to last,
可当她发现他们的婚姻只是父亲的
but her hopes of true love are crushed when she finds out
另一笔交易 她对于真爱的幻想破灭了
their marriage is just another one of daddy's business deals.
我可是同性恋
I'm gay.
我孙子也是同性恋
Oh! My grandson is gay.
他叫丹尼尔·舒曼 你认识吗
His name is Daniel Schulman. Uh, do you know him?
他是不是这么高 深色头发
Oh! Is he about this tall, dark hair,
割过包皮
circumcised?
你真坏
Terrible.
不要紧张 好吗
Don't be nervous, all right?
我会把你的情况说清楚
I'll explain your situation.
很快就能离开这里了
We'll have you out of here in no time.
县监狱关押30天
30 days in county jail.
-什么 -她好强硬
- What? - Ooh, she's tough.
下一个
Next.
安妮塔·曼查卡 偷窃
Anita Menchaca. Petty theft.
先生 您是律师吗
Mister, you're a lawyer?
帮帮我 拜托了
Help me, please.
不好意思 我是她的律师
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm her lawyer.
不不 帮帮她 这样能进行得快一些
No, no, help her, so this will go faster.
而且她让我想起了我外婆
And she reminds me of my abuela,
她也带这样的头巾 也曾偷窃
with her head scarf and her petty theft charges.
在这里 法官阁下
Here, your honor.
我是米奇尔·普里契特 "曼查勾"小姐的律师
I'm mitchell pritchett, attorney to miss Manchego.
-是曼查卡 -好的
- Menchaca. - Ah, yeah...
你们准备好辩诉了吗
Are you ready to enter a plea?
当然准备好了
Absolutely.
我认为这种事件完全没有理由
I see no reason why this matter should
占用更多贵法庭宝贵的时间了
take up any more of the court's valuable time.
无罪 法官大人
Not guilty, your honor.
为什么
Why?
我需要点时间准备一下
Gonna need a minute.
看我爸给了我什么
Look what my dad just gave me.
拜托你告诉我盒子里装的不是你妈
Please tell me that's not your mom.
不是 她已经给自己选好骨灰罐了
No, no. She picked out her own urn.
我爸一直都说
My dad keeps saying
那罐子小一码 不过她还是挤进去了
it's a size too small but she squeezed into it.
这些东西是她留给孩子们的
No, this is stuff she left for the kids.
-我能打开吗 -能啊
- Can I... open it? - Yeah.
里面有张纸条是给你的
Wow. There's a note for you.
我不敢看
I can't read it.
-好吧 -你来好吗
- Okay. - Would you?
好的
All right.
"亲爱的菲尔
"Dear phil,
你一直都是最棒的儿子
you've always been the most wonderful son,
而我现在需要你为我做最后一件事"
and now I need you to do one last thing for me."
不
Oh, no!
她一定是让我把她的骨灰泼到牧师脸上
She's gonna ask me to throw her ashes in the pope's face.
"不要告诉你父亲
"Don't say anything to your father
因为他一定会反对
because he'll just resist,
但是有一位名叫安妮·菲茨曼斯的女士
but there's a woman named Annie Fitzsimmons
她就住在几条街外
who lives a few streets over.
我们和她并不太熟 但我一向很欣赏她
We don't know her very well, but I've always admired her,
我觉得她会和你父亲很般配
and I think she'd be perfect for your dad.
因此 在你回家前
So before you go home,
我希望你能撮合他们"
I want you to fix him up with her."
这太疯狂了
That is crazy!
"我知道这听起来很疯狂
"I know this sounds crazy,
但这里的单身男士很紧俏
but single men are in short supply here.
会有一群工于心计的狐狸精
And a lot of scheming harpies will swoop in
在你父亲尚未察觉的情况下蜂拥而至
before your father knows what hit him.
我爱弗兰克
I love Frank,
但任何会做饭的女人都能牵着他鼻子走"
but he'll follow anything with a casserole."
我真觉得难以置信
I don't believe this.
这也太快了
It's too soon,
何况我爸又不是动画片里的熊熊
and my dad's not a cartoon bear.
他有足够的能力作出理智的判断
He's perfectly capable of making intelligent decisions.
爸妈 我做了饼干
Hey, guys? I made cookies.
太好了 我还以为是邻居家做的
Oh, good. I thought that was a neighbor.
孩子们 奶奶给你们每个人留了些东西
Hey, kids, your grandma left each of you something.
太棒了 是乐步鞋
Cool! Rockports!
只是用了鞋盒子而已
It's just the box.
我的天 有一封信
oh, my god. There's a letter.
我觉得我还没做好心理准备
I don't know if I'm ready for this.
尽管如果这是奶奶写的
Although if grandma wrote it,
她一定事先感觉到我已经准备好了
she must have sensed I was ready.
因为你俩有特殊的感情纽带吗
Because you had such a bond?
你也感觉到了吗
You felt it, too?
海莉 跟我们说说你那封信的内容
Haley, why don't you tell us what yours says?
写得真贴心
Well, it's so sweet.
是关于我的内在是多么美丽 还有
It's about how beautiful I am inside and--
帅啊 首饰
Score! Jewelry
快来看
Check it out!
看看
Oh, look at that.
你奶奶可喜欢怀表了
Your grandma loved pocket watches.
她说过怀表让人看起来很高贵
Aw! She said they made a man look dignified.
这条链子是为了防止有人吞下它吗
Is this chain in case you swallow it?
不是 但我突然好庆幸有这条链子
No, but suddenly I'm glad it's there.
-打火机 -信里怎么说
- A lighter? - Huh. What does the note say?
"这是一个打火机"
"This is a lighter."
我不明白
I don't understand.
你还要她说得多清楚呢
How much clearer could she have been?
我觉得你不要想太多了
I wouldn't read too much into it.
奶奶一直很爱你们
Your grandma loved you very much.
她只是在生命最后做了些奇怪的事情
She just did a couple of bizarre things towards the end.
艾丽克斯 我可以帮你
Here, Alex, I can help you out with that.
你现在很困很困想睡觉
You are getting very sleepy.
破烂旧打火机并不是个很糟的礼物
A crappy old lighter is not a sucky gift.
亲爱的 你不打算完成你妈妈的遗嘱吗
Honey, hey, hey. So you're not gonna do what your mom asked?
在她葬礼这天把我爸
Marry off my dad to a complete stranger
许配给一个陌生人吗 我想不会
on the day of her funeral? I think not.
这可是她的遗愿
It was her last wish.
等我爸准备好了
When my dad is ready,
他会去挑他喜欢的女友
he gets to pick his own girlfriend.
这可是妻子去世的一大好处
That's the big upside to your wife dying.
再就是 以后说话不用脑子也没事了
Also, not having to think before you speak.
是啊
Yeah.
法官阁下 这一切都归结于此
Your honor, it all boils down to this.
这家旅馆欠"曼查勾"小姐的
The motel owes Miss Menchengo--
-曼查卡 -该死 每次都错
- Menchaca. - Damn it. Every time.
薪水高于她拿走的
more in wages than she ever could've taken
香皂和超小瓶洗发水的价值
in soaps and tiny shampoos.
好吧 案件驳回
Fine. Case dismissed.
太好了
Yes!
谢谢 太谢谢了
Oh! Gracias! Muchas gracias!
-不客气 不客气 -太谢谢了
- De nada. De nada. - Muchas gracias.
看见没 我胜诉了
Did you see that? I won!
-真是不敢相信 -看到了
- I-I can't believe it! - Yeah.
你赢一次这么高兴 我很怕你胜诉率很低
It scares me that winning is such a surprise for you.
下一个 马修·普乐斯科 违规停车
Next! Matthew Plonsker. Parking violations.
我还以为会有点生疏 但显然没有
I thought I'd be a little rusty, but apparently not.
又来找我吗 真"好"呢
Oh! Really? Sweet.
去吧 把错误都犯在他身上
Yes! Go make your mistakes with him.
我可不想因为卖淫坐牢
I don't want to go to jail for prostitution.
你以为你能嫖得起我吗
Like you could afford me.
在我看来 在那个重要的下午
It seems to me it wasn't only the meter
并不只是停车计费表坏了
that was broken that fateful afternoon.
不仅如此
Nay!
是整个刑事司法系统坏了
It was the entire criminal justice system.
因此我要提出的是
Therefore I submit to you,
那晚影响我的客户判断力的唯一一样东西
the only "Influence" my client was under that night
就是他对划船的热爱
was his love of boating.
可耻啊
Shame!
我只是不懂 她为什么给我一个打火机
I just don't get it. Why would she give me a lighter?
也许她希望你把你所有丑衣服都烧掉
Maybe she wants you to burn all your clothes.
是不是我们并不像我想的那样有特殊的感情纽带
Is it possible we didn't have the connection I thought we did?
我不知道 你也听老爸说了
I don't know. You heard dad.
她去世前一直在接受药物治疗
She was on all that medication towards the end.
人们服药期间总会做些诡异的事
People do weird things when they're on drugs.
迪兰在牙根管治疗后服了止痛药
When Dylan was on vicodin after his root canal,
他买了一整套《女医生》光盘
he bought the complete DVD set of "Dr. Quinn Medicine Woman."
女孩们 请离开
Get going, ladies.
泳池只对当地居民开放
The pool's for residents only.
好的 对不起 我们这就走
Oh, okay. Sorry. We'll leave.
不 我们不走 这里又没人
Uh, no, we won't. There's nobody here.
-海莉 -为什么我们不能用这泳池
- Haley! - Why can't we use the pool?
这是规定
Because those are the rules.
有什么问题吗
Are we gonna have a problem here?
你可吓不着我 我蹲过真正的监狱
You don't scare me. I've been in real jail.
你俩是聪明人 不是吗
Oh, you two are pretty smart, aren't you?
不 只有她聪明
No. Only she is.
北风
North.
花牌
Flowers.
红中
Red.
一筒
One dot.
二条
Two bam.
我和了
I have mahj!
-嘻嘻 -你又和了
- Hee hee! - Again?!
你今天手气真好啊 伊迪丝
Wow, you're really on some streak, Edith.
走牌运啊
Luck of the tiles.
还有人要来点潘趣酒吗
Anyone else want some punch?
好啊 我也来点
Yeah. I'll join you.
你打得真不错
You are very good.
你这样的农场男孩是在哪里学的麻将
Where'd a farm boy like you learn to play mahjong?
在一个夏天
Oh, well, one summer,
我在中央密苏里圣约之子会工作
I worked at the Central Missouri b'nai b'rith.
是全国最小的分会
It's the nation's smallest chapter.
听我说 玛丽莲
Listen, Marilyn,
我不想挑拨离间的
I don't mean to stir things up,
但我看到伊迪丝从她口袋里拿了那张吊牌
But I just saw Edith take the winning tile out of her jacket pocket.
我就知道
I knew it!
没人会手气那么好
Nobody's that good!
我也跟你一样震惊
Listen, I'm as shocked as you are.
只是伊迪丝看上去不是那种人
It just doesn't seem like Edith.
是 就是这样 知人知面不知心
Yeah, well, it goes to show, you think you know someone...
饼干都去哪里了
What happened to all the cookies?
我真的不想挑拨离间的
Oh, well, you know I hate to stir things up...
-抱歉 -什么事
- Excuse me. - Yes?
我是杰·普里契特
Jay Pritchett.
弗兰克·邓菲是我亲家
Frank Dunphy's son is married to my daughter.
真是遗憾
Oh, I'm so sorry.
他那套幽默果然会传染身边人
Ah, he grows on you.
你是说很遗憾我亲家母过世 谢谢关心
Oh, you're talking about the death. Thank you.
我看你非常脸熟 你在俄亥俄生活过吗
You look very familiar to me. Did you ever live in Ohio?
没 我是彭萨科拉人
No. I'm from Pensacola.
然后我突然就想到了
And then it hit me.
我新兵入伍时 在彭萨科拉受过训
I had done my basic training in Pensacola.
她是我的初夜
She was my first.
我永远忘不了她 夏洛特什么的
I'll never forget her-- Charlotte somebody.
我当年18岁 她31岁
I was 18, and she was 31.
我们当时爱得死去活来
And we fell pretty hard for each other.
我从越战回来后就再没联系她
I always felt bad I never called her
心里一直很难受
when I got back from Vietnam.
尤其是因为当时我已经 你懂的
Especially because by then I had, you know...
已经开拓了新的眼界
learned a few things.
不好意思 请你谅解
I'm sorry. You'll have to forgive me.
我岁数大了 记性不好了
My memory isn't what it used to be.
我当时在海军 杰·普里契特
I was in the navy. Jay Pritchett.
当年头发多些
Little more up here,
赘肉少些
little less down here.
我敢说你一定是个好男人
I'm sure you're a very nice man,
但我觉得你把我错认成别人了
but I-I think you may have mistaken me for someone else.
我当时就快要被派往越南
I was shipping off to vietnam.
你当年的屁股就跟年轻女星安·玛格丽特一样
You had the ass of a young Ann Margret.
好吧 那确实是我
Yeah, that was me.
这张照片里奶奶真高兴
Grandma looks so happy here.
是啊 当时我们喝得烂醉
Yeah. We were pretty hammered.
那是去年的国庆节 你奶奶最喜欢的节日
That was last 4th of July-- grandma's favorite holiday.
普林朴顿家搞了烧烤
The Plimptons had a barbecue,
你奶奶和我喝姜汁玛格丽特喝多了
and Gram and I got a little tipsy on ginger margaritas.
我们就回家打了个盹
We came home for a catnap
结果错过了那晚的烟花表演
and slept right through the big fireworks show.
她头一回错过
First one she ever missed.
她当时特别生气
Boy, was she mad.
我为了补偿她
I made it up to her
当天晚些时候特意为她办了一场烟火表演
with a little fireworks show of our own later.
爷爷
Grandpa!
只是在后院用弹弓发射荧光棒而已
A couple of glow sticks and a slingshot in the backyard.
但接下来的性爱值得我们回味一生
Which led to some pretty memorable lovemaking.
我不是故意转移话题
Not to change the subject,
但我真不懂奶奶送这个给我的意义
but I don't really get the gift grandma left me.
她在信里没解释吗
Well, didn't she explain it in the note?
没 信里就几个字
No. The note's four words.
你知道这纸还要展开的吧
You know it opens, right?
是吗
It does?
当然 佛罗里达太潮湿了 东西都黏一块了
Sure. Look, it's Florida. Everything sticks together.
真是太诡异了
It's all so weird.
心里一直害怕面对的事
This thing you dread in the back of your mind
突然就成真了
suddenly becomes real.
我懂
I know.
不过有你在 我感觉好多了
I feel better having you here, though.
我会永远在你身边
Oh, I'm always here for you.
看那房子
Look at that house.
真漂亮啊
That is a cute house.
我想知道谁住这儿
I wonder who lives there.
我不知道
I don't know.
克莱尔 你要干嘛
Claire, what are you doing?
我喜欢这房子
I love this house.
我敢肯定不管是谁住这儿 我都会喜欢那人
I bet you anything I would love whoever lives here.
等等
Wait a minute.
我妈信上说的人就住这儿 是吧
That lady from my mom's letter lives here,doesn't she?
安妮·菲茨曼斯
Annie Fitzsimmons.
菲尔 听我说
Phil, listen to me.
你也许有理由不想这么做
You may have your reasons for not wanting to do this,
但你母亲是个很英明的女人
but your mother was a very wise woman.
她相信这扇门背后的那个人
She believed that whoever is behind that door
能让你父亲拥有幸福的余生
would make your father happy for the rest of his life.
你们好 有事吗
Yeah. What can I do for you?
她真"完美"
She's perfect.
我以为安妮·菲茨曼斯住这儿
I thought Annie Fitzsimmons lived here.
是的 安妮 亲爱的
She does. Annie, honey!
有人想见你
There's people here to see ya!
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
有事吗
Can I help you?
我们是推销吸尘器的
We're selling vacuum cleaners.
那可真奇怪
That is strange.
我知道
I know.
因为我家吸尘器早上正好坏了
Because just this morning, my vacuum cleaner broke.
都怪我 我的体毛脱落像牧羊犬那么多
That's on me. I shed like a collie.
我看看你们的货
Let's see what you got.
对啊 克莱尔 来看看你的货
Yes, Claire, let's see what you got.
我没带来
I didn't bring it.
-你没带 -是的
- You didn't bring it? - No.
我们出门时你还带着的啊
You had it when we left the vacuum cleaner office.
我看这下你要好好认错了
I guess it's fair to say you've made a huge mistake.
不行 要说出来
No. Say it.
我也不想为难她 可这就是培训
I'm sorry to do that. It's part of the training.
我犯了个大错
I've made a huge mistake.
我觉得她是不适合干这行的
I don't think she's gonna work out.
-我又和了 -真厉害
- That's mahj again! - Oh! Well, shocker.
-够了 你出老千 -我没有
- That's it. You're cheating. - I am not.
得了吧 你藏的牌
Oh, please! You've stashed more tiles
比玛丽莲藏的饼干还多
than Marilyn has cookies!
好了 大家先歇歇
O-okay. Uh, let's just take a breath.
谁在乎麻将牌啊 饼干啊
Who cares about tiles or cookies
或者海蒂偷偷往她的咖啡里倒的什东西
Or whatever Hattie's slipping into her coffee?
我就知道你又开始酗酒了
I knew you were drinking again!
她的驾照就是这么被吊销的
That's how she lost her license.
闭上你们的臭嘴
You shut your traps!
-去死吧 -去你的
- Drop dead! - Screw you!
-你也是 -女士们
- Yeah, you, too! Ladies.
- And you! - Ladies.
别说了 别吵了
Stop it! You--stop it.
你们都当了20年的闺蜜了
You have been friends for 20 years.
你们这是怎么回事啊
What on earth has gotten into you all?
为什么我到哪都会碰上极品事呢
Why does drama keep following me everywhere I go?
总是无缘无故就冒一出
It just keeps popping up out of nowhere.
跟克里斯宾脑袋上冒出来的头发似的
like Crispin's hair plugs.
然后我们去了你的公寓
And so we went to your apartment.
到现在我还是觉得很丢人
It's still embarrassing.
我当时告诉你我从没跟女人做过
I told you I had never been with a woman.
你牵着我的手 带我进了卧室
And you took me by the hand and you led me into the bedroom.
你是那么温柔美丽
You were so sweet and beautiful.
那一刻我感觉自己到了天堂
I thought I'd gone to heaven.
-杰·普里契特 -是我 就是我
- Jay pritchett. - Yes! Yes!
我想起来了
I remember that.
你那会可真帅呀
You were so handsome.
我可不敢说自己帅
I don't know about that.
可能还算讨人喜欢
I mean, cute, maybe.
是常有人夸我的眼睛迷人来着
I--people talk about my eyes.
我一直很后悔回来后没再联系你
But I always regretted not getting in touch with you when I got back,
因为你带给我的美好回忆
Because you had given me something
我已经珍惜了差不多50年了
that I cherished for almost 50 years.
你也给了我些东西
You gave me something, too.
是吗
I did?
你在这儿乖乖等着
You wait right there.
我去那是为了参加一个葬礼
I'm down there for a funeral--
原本是很悲伤的一件事
It's such a sad event--
我却找到了本以为已经永远失去了的东西
And I end up finding something that I thought was lost forever.
当年那美妙的"小插曲"
This beautiful moment
对我们都有着难以取代的意义
that meant so much to both of us,
尤其是在反击越共的时代大背景下
set against the backdrop of fighting commies.
简直能拍部电影啊
There's your movie.
我清楚地记得你把这东西给我时我在哪儿
I remember exactly where I was when you gave it to me.
你当时说"戴上这个手..."
You said, "Wear this bec--"
不 这不是我的
No, no. This isn't mine.
我从来没上过杰弗逊高中
And I never went to Jefferson High.
噢 是我搞错了
Oh. My mistake.
是这个
Here it is.
-你当时说"戴上这个..." -不对不对
- You said, "Pin this--" - No, no. N-no.
我从来没得过什么奖牌
Never got a medal.
而且...
And, uh...
我参的也不是这支军
This is the wrong branch of service.
当然了
Of course.
这些是...
These are th--
从没写过信
Never wrote.
你要不自己找吧
Why don't you look through here?
原来她送上战场的军人
Turns out she sent more men off to war
比林顿·约翰逊还要多
than Lyndon Johnson.
到家了
Well, we're here.
你要不要试试向我爸推销个吸尘器
You wanna try to sell my dad a vacuum?
你就嘲笑我吧
Tease me all you want.
我很高兴至少我们试过了
I am glad that we at least tried.
我知道你是好心 但他一个人也会过得很好
I know you mean well, but he's gonna be fine on his own.
太好笑了
So funny.
来 尝尝我做的 弗兰克
Ooh! Here. Try mine, Frank.
我敢说一定很好吃
I bet it's delicious.
除非你味觉挂了
If your taste buds are dead.
"挂了" 你真会照顾别人的心情 米娜
Dead? Real sensitive, Myra.
他妻子尸骨都未寒呢
The woman's not even cold...
当然你的奶酪茄子是早凉了
unlike your eggplant parm.
这演的是哪出
What is going on?
鲨鱼群争食呢 你爸爸就是那可怜的食物
Oh, it's a feeding frenzy. They're all over him.
她们还量了窗户的尺寸 想换新窗帘呢
They're practically measuring the windows for new drapes.
真把我恶心坏了
It's disgusting.
你一定要把这个食谱给我 米娜
I must get this recipe, Myra.
当然
Oh, sure.
你要那食谱吗 解冻 加热 端上来就行了
You want the recipe? It's thaw, heat, and serve.
我妈妈说得对 她们会把他生吞了
My mom was right. They're gonna eat him alive.
你觉得我们有能力拆散
Do you think we can break up
安妮·菲茨曼斯和她男朋友吗
Annie fitzsimmons and her boyfriend?
男朋友
Boyfriend?
你是说马维 哎呀妈 太好笑了
Oh, you mean Marv? Oh, that's hilarious.
马维是她哥哥 从庞帕诺来玩的
Marv's her brother, visiting from Pompano.
他仅仅是过来度周末的
he's here for the week,
这地方一半的女人都跟他有一腿
Slept with half the women in this place.
她现在单身 真是太棒了
She's single? This is fantastic.
小卡 你都是打哪知道的
Cam, how do you know that?
这地方的八卦简直满天飞
This place is lousy with gossips.
下一个 歌洛莉亚·迪尔加多
Next. Gloria Delgado?
我在这儿
I'm here!
协同卖淫罪 你打算怎么辩护
Conspiring to promote prostitution. How do you plead?
-无罪 法官大人 -老天 又是你
-Not guilty, your honor. - Oh, good. It's you.
陛下 我什么坏事都没干
Your Majesty, I didn't do anything wrong.
但我愿意认罪
But I will say that I am guilty
如果交了罚金就能让我回家的话
if I can just pay the fine and go home.
不 你不能
No, you won't.
你是清白的 我能证明这点
You're innocent, and I can prove it.
法官大人 这份文件表明
Your honor, this document here shows
我的当事人当时正住在加利福尼亚
that my client was a resident of California at the time.
这些已兑支票表明
And these canceled checks prove
她合法转租了本案所指的那套公寓
that she was legally subletting the apartment in question.
我这人挺单纯的 但我知道一件事
I might be a simple man, but I do know one thing...
如果狗不吠
if a dog don't bark--
够了 我再也不想听他扯犊子了
Okay, I can't listen to him anymore.
此案驳回 休庭
Case dismissed. Court adjourned.
谢谢你 米奇尔 你太厉害了
Gracias, Mitchell! You're wonderful!
其实 算我们走运
You know what? We got lucky
"狗不吠"那句我都不知道怎么往下接
because I had no ending to that dog thing.
如果你下周不忙的话
If you don't have anything to do next week,
也许可以陪我去趟德州
maybe you can go with me to Texas.
再次打扰
Hello again.
不是吧 你一个人
Oh, no. You're alone.
你炒掉了那个可爱姑娘吗
Did you fire that nice girl?
不 她不是什么可爱姑娘 她是我老婆
No. She's not a nice girl. She's my wife.
我们也不是卖吸尘器的
And we don't sell vacuums.
谢天谢地 否则你们会饿死的
Thank god. You'd starve.
其实我是菲尔·邓菲
I-I-I'm actually Phil Dunphy.
我是弗兰克和格蕾丝·邓菲的儿子
I-I'm Frank and Grace Dunphy's son.
我听说了你母亲去世的事 太遗憾了
Oh, I heard about your mom. I'm--I'm so sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
我只见过她几次
I only met her a few times,
但她看起来是个非常好的人
but she seemed like a lovely woman.
但我还是不太明白你的来意
but I'm still confused.
也许我的解释只会令你更困惑 但是
Well, this probably won't help, but, um...
她的遗愿就是叫我撮合你和我爸
Her last request was for me to fix you up with my dad.
我的天
Oh, my.
是啊 我真希望自己是卖吸尘器的
Yeah. I really wish I sold vacuums.
所以之前
So earlier...
我们看到你哥哥来开门 十分震惊
We were thrown when your brother answered the door.
我们以为他是你的男友
We thought he was your boyfriend.
我不知道说什么好
I don't know what to say.
是吗 我这个要求再正常不过了
Really? This is such a-a normal request I'm making.
顺便说下 请不要感觉有任何压力
Please, by the way, don't feel pressured at all.
我爸根本不知道这件事
My dad doesn't even know about this.
但我必须告诉你 这是我母亲的遗愿
I-I just--I had to tell you. It's what she wanted.
她总是会做这样疯狂的事
She was always doing crazy stuff like this...
不遗余力地照顾我们
going out of her way to take care of us.
有次我在电话里咳嗽
I coughed on the phone once,
她就熬汤连夜快递给我
and she overnighted me soup.
我想学滑雪 她就给我织毛衣
When I wanted to learn how to ski, she knit me a sweater.
我想做海洋生物学家
When I wanted to be a marine biologist,
她就给我织了件鲸鱼图案的毛衣
she knit me a sweater with a whale on it.
谁会这样做啊
Who does that?
她就是这样的人
That's just the kind of person she is.
生前是
Was.
亲爱的
Oh, sweetie.
你是个好儿子
You're a good son.
她说的对 你是个非常好的人
She was right. You are very nice.
仪式太感人了
It's a beautiful service.
让人思考要如何度过这一生
It really makes you think about how you wanna live your life.
我想辞职 重返法庭
I wanna quit my job and get back into the courtroom.
什么
What?
先别对任何人说起这事
Just--just don't say anything to anyone.
我能告诉谁啊
Well, who am I gonna tell?
谢谢 梅尔
Thank you, Mel.
你吹奏得很美
That was beautiful.
在我们道晚安前
Um, before we say good night,
我女儿艾丽克斯想致以悼念
my daughter Alex would like to pay tribute.
谢谢 宝贝
Thanks, sweetie.
奶奶和我有着特殊的感情纽带
My grandmother and I had a very special bond.
不是吧 又来
Seriously? Again?
也许大家不理解
This may not make sense to everyone,
但我肯定 奶奶会喜欢的
but I'm pretty sure she would've loved it.
"这是一个打火机
"This is a lighter.
原本属于我最喜欢的演员 保罗·纽曼
It belonged to my favorite actor, Paul Newman.
有一天 他来我做服务员的餐厅就餐
One day, he came into the restaurant where I was waitressing
不小心落下了
and accidentally left it behind.
我这辈子第一次
For the first time in my life,
做了不应该做的事
I did something I wasn't supposed to
将之据为己有
and slipped it into my pocket.
有一位客人看到了
One of the customers saw
说 "别担心 我会帮你保守秘密"
and said, 'don't worry. Your secret's safe with me.'
那位客人后来成为了我的毕生挚爱
That customer turned out to be the love of my life,
你的爷爷
your grandfather.
所以 我最爱的艾丽克斯
So, my Alex, who I love so dearly,
可能你太像我了 虽然这也挺好
who is probably too much like me for her own good,
但偶尔的
every once in a while,
不要害怕打破常规
don't be afraid to break the rules.
你永远不知道会发生什么好事
You never know what can happen."
天气怎么样
How 'bout this weather?
还行 他们说要下雨了
Yep. They say it's supposed to rain.
确实需要来场雨
We need it.
穆丽尔
Muriel.
你们两个收拾好准备走了吗
Are you two packed up and ready to go?
是的
Yep.
时间怎么过得这么快
Where does the time go?
鬼才知道
Darned if I know.
大家总是匆匆忙忙的
Everyone's always in such a hurry.
何必如此 我们最后的归宿还不都一样
And why? We're all gonna end up in the same place.
我觉得我们还是走吧
Well, I guess we better mosey.